<chapter>
<title>Introduction</title>

<sect1>
<title>Acknowledgements</title>
<para>There are many people who have helped out with this project, in ways ranging from words of encouragement to listening to me rant when I had errors that resulted from typos to contributions of code. To name any subset of these people would do a diservice to those whom I left out, and as I really don't remember who has helped (aside from 'everyone') and what role they played, I am not going to name any people here. Instead, I will simply say "Many thanks to everyone who has helped. You guys rock."</para>
</sect1>

<sect1>
<title>About Dryad</title>
<para>UNIX machines document everything. Everytime something happens, a log message is created. This is both the worst nightmare and greatest asset to a good network administrator. Important events, from hardware failure to attacks on systems, are noted by the system and recorded. However, there is a two fold problem with this default setup. First, the messages need to get off of the generating device; it doesn't do much good to have notification of hardware failure on a broken harddrive, or information about the comprimising of a system in the hands of the attacker. Secondly, the valuable information needs to be sorted from the noise of regular workings. Dryad aims to provide this by being both a remote log server, and a real time processor of log information.</para>
</sect1>

<sect1>
<title>Intended Audience</title>
<para>This document is aimed at implementors of Dryad installations. While it may be interesting to other people, its primary purpose is to explain how to work with Dryad as a user.</para>
</sect1>

<sect1>
<title>Copying</title>
<para>This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike License. To view a copy of this license, visit <ulink url="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/1.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/1.0/</ulink> or send a letter to Creative Commons, 559 Nathan Abbott Way, Stanford, California 94305, USA.</para>
</sect1>

</chapter>
